<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-marie-curie</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88068010/1899-07-28/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Curie+radium&st=text&r=-0.246,-0.075,1.491,1.491,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ANOTHER NEW ELEMENT 
  Three French chemists M. and Mine, 
Curie and M. Bemont have discovered a
new metallic element, which they call 
"radium," because of its remarkable 
property of emitting rays
which resemble in their penetrative
power Prof. Roentgen's celebrated X
rays. Not long ago much surprise was
caused by the discovery that uranium
is capable of emitting similar rays, but
the power of radium in this respect is
Eaid to be 900 times greater than that
of uranium.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1899-12-17/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Curie+Curies+polonium+Polonium&st=text&r=-0.056,-303.144,1.111,607.778,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A NEW CHEMICAL ELEMENT 
  The investigations of M. and Mme. Curie,
which resulted in the finding of radium, began
early. In 1898 if not before, hand were doubtless
stimulated, if not suggested, by the Bl
varian professors brilliant achievement. Rontgen's 
work naturally called to mind the observation 
of Becquerel, that uranium and its
salts exerted a very feeble photographic in
fluence. By experimenting with pitchblende,
the mineral from which uranium is obtained 
commercially, M. and Mme. Curie found that
the former yielded the same effect much more
cnnaplcuoualy. This led them to suspect that
they were on the track of a new element. They
even went so far as to name it proivisionally,
although much difficulty was experienced in 
seperating it from the substances with which
it was associated. Just before the close of the
year, with the co-operation of M. Bemont, they
obtained indications of still another new ele
ment The first they called "polonium'' and the
second "radium.' Polonium is believed to
surpass uranium and its salts in amissive power
five hundredfold, but Professor Barker estimates
the effiency of radium at one hundred thou¬
sand times that of uranium. For this reason,
and because of its comparative cheapness and 
simplicity, the second of the Curies' discoveries
seems destined to replace the costly and com
plicated X ray apparatus in the realm of
surgery.
    </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1899-12-31/ed-1/?sp=23&q=Curie+Curies+radium&st=text&r=-0.251,-0.075,1.502,1.502,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE CATHODE RAY OUTDONE
  WHEN the marvels of the cathode or X ray
were made known to the world only a few
years ago, it was believed we had reached a
degree of photographic power that would not be sur
passed for generations to come, and that for the use
of surgeons in locating foreign substances imbedded
in flesh or bone it would be of permanent value. Yet
according to reports of experiments made by Pro
fessor Barker in Philadelphia a short time ago, that
wonderful ray is about to become a back number be
cause of the potency shown by a newly discovered
element known as "radium."
The discovery of the new element is due to M. and
lime. Curie and is the result of investigations stimu
lated by the discovery of the X-ray. They were ex
perimenting in 1898 with uranium and its salts, which
exert a feeble photographic power, when they ob
served phenomena indicating the existence of an un
known factor in the mass. They at once directed
their investigations to the separation of that element
from the substances with which it was associated
and found not one but two new elements. To the first
they gave the name "polonium" and to the second
'•radium." The first is believed to have a radiant
power five hundredfold greater than that of uranium,
but Professor Barker estimates the efficiency of ra
dium at one hundred thousand times that of uranium.
For this reason and because of its comparative cheap
ness and simplicity the second of the Curies' discov
eries seems destined, it is said, to replace the costly
and complicated X-ray apparatus in the realm of sur
gery.
The most extraordinary characteristic of the new
element is thus described in an account of Professor
Barker's experiments by the New York Tribune:
"The practicability of deriving one form of energy
heat, light, electricity or chemical action— from
some other has long been recognized, but it is axiom
atic that none of them can be produced except by that
method. It is believed that the most man can do is
to transform. It is thought that he cannot, in any
true sense, create. Roentgen obtained his X-rays
only by a conversion of force previously existing in
the form of electricity. But a radiance which will
penetrate opaque bodies and act upon the chemicals
on a photographic plate is secured from radium with
out the apparent use of any known species of energy.
The phenomenon may yet be explained. But at pres
ent it looks very much like what has long been re
garded an impossibility, the spontaneous generation
of force."
The discovery of unknown elements of such mar
velous potencies at this late stage in the investigations
of science is a striking proof of how little we know
of the substances that lie around us or of the forces
that act upon them. There is no telling wlrit wide
and high uses may yet be made of radium, but it is
probable the discovery will be one of the most im
portant gifts which this century v:ill bestow for the
guidance of science in that which is to come
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86069457/1900-03-08/ed-1/?sp=7&q=Curie+RADIUM+radium&st=text&r=-0.301,-0.08,1.602,1.602,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A NEW CHEMICAL WHICH IS BETTER THAN THE X-RAY
  A New Chemical Which Is Better
Than the X Ray
Prof Ri orgc F Barker of the phy
sical laboratory of tho University of
Pennsylvania exhibited lut week for
the first time In America the newly
discovered chemical element radium
which seems destined to create a groat
stir In the scientific world Yearn ago
Bequercl found that Halts of the ruie
metal uranium posesirod the power of
throwing off a feeble and Invisible ra
diance like the X rnys Mine Curie In
lnrls last year Isolated from the Bo
hemian mineral pltchblend two other
elements that hehavc In tho Mime man
ner but are far more active One of
them she called polonium anil tho
other milium The latter Is said to
be 100000 times as Intense as uranium
In Its photographic effect
Trof Binkcr has been experimenting
with nil three of these elements and
with the mineral pltchblend or lira
nlte from which the tVB now ele
ments nro derived He showed to the
Bibliographical Club here this week a
heiies of photographic plates on which
Impressions had been produced by
these substances Ills pioccdure has
been as follows
A photographic plate was Inclosed
in black paper and then coveted with
yellow paper After one whole days
exposure to tho sunlight no effect was
produced This piecnutlon proved the
thoroughness of the protection Then
the various metals and salts were
placed upon tho paper covered plate
and they produced dark stains
In order to take photographs of ob
jects such as n hand or foot these ob
jects would he placed between tho met
nl and the plate and the result would
be similar to those obtained by the
X rays such substances as bone would
show dearly through the tlosh and sur
rounding tlt suc A photograph can be
taken by means of radium In half a
minute
The Importance of this discovery
can hardly be overestimated The won
derful results of the X rays now so
usoful In surgical diagnosis au be du
plicated by a method much cheaper
Moreover radium seems to suffer no
diminution of energy or loss of weight
during tho process In nddltlon to pro
ducing nn Impression on th6 photo
graphic plate radium produces phos
phorescence and discharges electrified
bodies Thus It will be seen thnt it
possesses nil tho qualities of tho Ro
entgen rays
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085421/1907-05-13/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Curie+Marie+Sklodowska&st=text&r=-0.203,-0.07,1.406,1.406,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WOMEN WHO DO
  The First Woman Professor In the
Famous Sorbonne University at
Paris —Mme. Curie as She Ap
pears When Lecturing
A slender, youthfnl woman in deep
mourning, ber fair hair swept plainly
back from a remarkably broad, high.
full brow, her head seemingly almost
too large for the slim neck that car
ried it. her manner so simple, so un
conscious and sincere that it was child
like—such was the appearance of Mmc
Curie as she stood in a class room de
livering the first lecture ever given by
a woman professor to the students of
the University of Paris. It was an
event which should make women all
over the world rejoice and take cour
age, because at last the earnest, de
voted scientific work of one of their
MME. CLXIX LECTURING.
sex has been fittingly recognized.
Mme. Marie Sklodowska Curie, discov
erer of radium. Is by birth it Pole. Her
father was a professor of sciences in
the town where Marie spent her child
hood, and she was interested in re
torts, test tubes and chemicals at an
age when girl children are expected to
play with dolls. But little Marie never
did play with dolls. She used to spend
her time In tbe professor's laboratory
and frequently amazed with her wis
dom and knowledge grave, learued
meu who called on her father. After
finishing the scientific course in the
school of her borne town of Varsovie
the young girl went to Paris to study
further. There she met Pierre Curie,
student of chemistry, as enthusiastic as
herself. They were at once drawn to
each other and in time were married.
Dorothy Levitt, English Automo
bilist.
When Dorothy Levitt, a London girl,
was twenty years old her parents tried
to make her marry a man she disliked.
She would not and ran away from
home. Through a friend she was en
abled to go to Paris and work in an
automobile factory, where she wore
overalls, learned her business and
minded It. She returned to London
and got employment teaching women
to operate automobiles. From In
structor in automobillng Dorothy Lev
itt turned to motor racing and quickly
became tbe woman champion speeder
of Europe. She has twice reached the
dizzy rate of 100 miles an hour with
her eighty power machine. Miss Lev
itt has developed also unusual commer
cial talent in connection with the auto
mobile business, and her income is $10,-
--000 a year. She has challenged any
woman automobilist in America to race
with her.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047084/1910-05-15/ed-1/?sp=14&q=Curie+CURIE+Marie+Sklodowska&st=text&r=-0.376,-0.141,1.752,1.752,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  The fame acquired some years ago by Mme. 
  Marie Sklodowska Curie by her discovery 
  of radium promises to be equaled, if not
  surpassed, by the honors which have come 
  to her as the discoverer some months ago 
  of the new, even more wonderful, element 
  polonium. It was as a coworker with her 
  husband, the late Professor Curie, that 
  this brilliant woman succeeded in isolating 
  radium, and it is now with the assistance of 
  M. de Bierne that she has succeeded in isolating 
  the tenth part of a milligram of polonium. This 
  substance, 5000 times rarer than radium taking 
  its name from her native Poland, was the product 
  of the chemical treatment of more than five tons 
  of pitchblende with hydrochloric acid. Polonium 
  "wastes away" with great rapidity, a thousand times 
  quicker than radium. Of course, the value of this 
  discovery is as yet purely scientific in a theoretical sense.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045396/1911-12-11/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Curie+Marie+Nobel+NOBEL+prize</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NOBEL PRIZES ARE GIVEN TO WINNERS 
Mme. Marie Curie Receives
Nearly 4O,oou for Her
Work in Chemistry.
STOCKHOLM, Dec, 10. King Gustav
today presented the Nobel prises, with
th exception of the peace prize, to the
wihners. Mine. Afavrie Sklodowska Curls
personally receix-od the prize for chem
istry: Professor Wiih' lm Wien of Wuerse
burr university the prise for physics, and
Professor Ailvar Gulls trend of Upsals
University tho prize for medicine Th
Belgian minister received the prir for
literature in behalf of Maurice Maeter
linck, who IS ill.
The Nobel prize each amounted to
nearly $4ft.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1911-11-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Curie+Marie+NOBEL+Nobel+prize+Prize+Prizes+prizes</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WOMEN WINS NOBEL CHEMISTRY AWARD
Mme. Curte, Discoverer o! Ra
dium and Polonium, Given
$40,000 Prize
STOCKHOLM. Nov. 7.—The Nobel
prize for chemistry has been awarded
to Mme. Marie Sklodowska Curie of the
University of Paris.
Mme. Curie is the chief professor of
sciences in the University of Paris. She
was the discoverer, with her husband.
Prof. Pierre Curie, of radium, and in
1903 shared with him half of the Xobel
pflze for physics, the other half being
awarded to Prof. Antoine Henri Bec
queret. Each of the five Nobel prizes
awarded annually amounts to $40,000.
Recent announcement was made of
the success of Mme. Curie in producing
polonium, "a new element possessing a
radio activity superior to radium."
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024827/1912-05-02/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Curie+DISCOVERIES+discoveries+Discovery+Marie+radium&st=text&r=-0.2,-0.041,1.4,1.4,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>"MME. CURIE, NOTED FRENCH SCIENTIST WINS NOBEL PRIZE FOR DISCOVERIES
  Mme. Marie Curie.
Ileie is ihe latent photograph of Mme Mane Curie the great French
scientist, who, with her husland, discovered radium Mme Curie is
without doubt the greatest of all women scientists She was rccentlv
the recipient ot theJNobel prize for her wondertul scientific chemical dis
co cries.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063381/1921-04-05/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Curie+Marie+radium&st=text&r=0.027,0.355,0.37,0.354,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>AN IMMORTAL WOMAN
The visit of Madam Marie Curie to this country in May
will be celebrated by American women with the presentation
of a thimbleful of radium to the distinguished scientist. At was
a beautiful tribute to the modesty of womankind that Mine.
Curie made when she discovered the element which has revo-
lutionized physics, chemistry and some branches of medicine,
and gave it an impersonal name. The courtesy of the labora-
-tory dictates that the discoverer of a new thing under the sun
may give it his own name if he wishes, and so perpetuate nia
own glory. Mme. Curie called it radium, because it gives out
HINTS TO GARDENERS
More than sentiment attaches to the gift. Of course, it
money value, something like $100,000, will have little weight
with a devotee of science like Mme. Curie.: She will use the
radium for scientific research. Although Mme. Curie knows
more concerning radium and its potentialities than any living
soul, she has not, because of her generosity, one grain with
which to conduct experiments.
The history of the discovery of radium is one of the most
exalted romances that the world has ever known. The daugh-
ter of a professor in the University of Warsaw, the present Mme.
Curie was drawn to Paris by the magnetic pull of the renowned
scientific schools there. In conjunction with the scientists
Becquerel and Curie, she began a series of experiments with
uranium which led to her discovery of radium. It also led to
her happy marriage with Professor Curie. That the discovery
was that of Mme. Curie alone was well established by a com-
mission which awarded her the Nobel prize in 1903.
The hope which radium holds out to the world is that it
may be the means of fighting cancer, that malignant disease
which has baffled physicians for centuries. Undoubtedly there
are new fields into which researchers can go. And it is in these
unexplored regions that Mme. Curie will venture. The women
of America honor themselves by providing the means.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/77618337/1943-09-20/ed-1/seq-17/#date1=1756&index=3&rows=20&words=Curie+Marie&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=MARIE+CURIE&y=15&x=11&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>Her Reading gave birth
bao, to a New Science
loved and transferred this affection to his chil
dren. For years he read to them, hour after hour, great
stories of travel, adventure and the literary masterpieces
of the past.
And so, alone in that country house, the young
governess turned to books as her teachers. She read
everything. She borrowed books from visitors to her
employer’s factory. She locked herself in her room at
night to read them.
Referring to the hundreds of books she read,
Madame Curie was to write forty years later, "As /
tried gradually to discover my true preferences, l finally
turned toward mathematics and physics.”
Thus, reading lighted her way to a new discovery
radium—that gave birth to a new science, a new
philosophy, and provided mankind with the means of
treating a dreadful disease.
Reading IS THI KEY that unlocks the door to the world’s
great storehouse of knowledge. Just as Madame Curie was
first inspired to begin her own brilliant researches, so read-
If it had not been for
the guidance of a devoted
father, Marie Curie might
have spent her lifetime as
an obscure governess in a
small Polish town.
But Marie Curie’s father
AUTOMOTIVE NEWS, SEPTEMBER 20, 1943
ing has helped many others grow to greatness. It affects the
lives of us all.
Today— The American Weekly is helping to cultivate and
develop this priceless habit of reading in more than 7,900,000
American homes. Its fascinating stories of real people grip
the imagination of millions. Its stirring tales of love and
crime, mystery and adventure satisfy the human hunger for
romance and excitement. Readers see themselves in these
daring roles and romantic intrigues, because the characters
are real people: the stories are true to life, dealing with
fundamental human interests.
Recalling Madame Curie’s passionate interest in science,
there is today a widespread thirst for scientific knowledge,
which The American W'eekly satisfies with its up-to-the-minute
reporting of the newest developments in the fields of physics,
chemistry, medicine, an, philosophy, education and religion.
These anicles are so authentic and advanced that teachers
and scientific institutions all over the country constantly use
faint blaitb light glimmtring from tiny glau tabat ms tbt magic new mbuanct tbt bad JitcavaraJ.
this material. Yet it is so simply and clearly written a child
can read and understand.
Of course, this widely read magazine is not especially
edited for the scientist or the scholar. It does not aim to
teach medicine to the doctor, nor history to the professor.
But among its millions of readers are thousands whose
lifelong interest in particular fields of learning was first
stimulated by the vivid impression gained from the reading
of an article in The American W'eekly.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn78002169/1943-10-10/ed-1/seq-16/#date1=1756&index=7&rows=20&words=Curie+Marie&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=MARIE+CURIE&y=15&x=11&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
    <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1929-11-03/ed-1/seq-125/#date1=1756&index=4&rows=20&words=Curie+Marie&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=MARIE+CURIE&y=15&x=11&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>Mme. Marie Curie, co-discoverer of radium, walking with
Owen D. Young after the ceremony at which she dedicated
the Hepburn Hall of Chemistry at St. Lawrence University.
Canton N Y. The famous scientist has just been a visitor at the 
White House.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1959-10-25/ed-1/seq-205/#date1=1756&index=18&rows=20&words=Curie+Marie&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=MARIE+CURIE&y=15&x=11&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>"Modame Curie."
1943. The story of Marie and
Pierre Curie who loved each other
as much as they did their work.A movie
on her story.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn96076839/1921-06-10/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=CURIE+Curie+MARIE+Marie&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=4&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=MARIE+CURIE&y=15&x=11&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>MME. MARIE CURIE.
New York Columbia university has
bestowed upon Madame Marie Curie,
co-discoverer of radium, the honorary
degree of doctor of sciences.
Since her arrival in the United
States a few weeks ago, Mme. Curie
has been signally honored by several
of the universities of the country.
President Harding has pesented her
with $100,000 worth of radium, the gift
of American women. 
</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-cassius-marcellus-clay-jr</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016804/1960-03-18/ed-1/?sp=7&q=clay%2C+cassius+olympics&st=text&r=0.442,0.737,0.2,0.239,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>LOUISVILLE CUTIE WINS TOP HONORS IN GOLDEN GLOVES
  A cheering
crowd of 11.159 fans who attended
the 33rd annual Tournament of
Champions Golden Gloves copeti
tion in the Chicago Stadium last
Wednesday night may well have
watched a future world champion.
He is 18-year-old Cassius Clay,
a boxing cutie from Louisville,
who won top honors during the
tournament by defeating Jimmy
Jones of Chicago for the heavy
weight crown. Jones was the de
fending champ.
Clay, who was also the 1959
light heavyweight champion, mov
ed up into the heavier division with
ease with a masterful exhibition of
boxing skill.
In their bout, televised nation
wide along with three others on
the card. Clay jabbed, shifted out
of range, countered and generally
outboxed Jones, whose knockout
punch was held a big threat for
his opponent.
Boxed I.ike Veteran
In fact. Clay boxed so well that
there were those at ringside who
thought he could start out right
now as a winning pro. He fought
so much like a veteran Incident
ally. Cassius’ younger brother was
eliminated earlier in the tourna
ment in a bid for the light heavy
weight crown.
Sharing championship honors
with Clay was another talented
tan fighter, Jefferson Davis of
Nashville. Dans, an all-out clouter.
defeated Bill Joiner of Cincinnati
in an action-packed three rounder,
that was also televised.
In winning his bout on decision.
Clay used a stabbing left jab and
follow-up right to beat Jones.
Davis lashed out with savage
rights and lefts to halt his man
after Joiner had given him sev
eral unpleasant moments in the
first round.
Clay and Davis were the only
two champions among the eight
crowned Wednesday night. But
they left no doubt that they were just about the best of the number.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84021918/1960-09-09/ed-1/?sp=7&q=clay%2C+cassius+olympics&st=text&r=0.289,0.631,0.39,0.466,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CLAY WINS OLYMPIC GOLD
Cassius Marcellus Clay, of
Louisville, Ky., won a gold medal
for the U. S. Olympic boxing
team in the heavyweight boxing
division.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92063852/1962-10-20/ed-1/?dl=page&q=clay%2C+cassius+marcellus</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82001257/1963-03-07/ed-1/?sp=13&q=knockout+cassius+clay&st=text&r=-0.081,0.66,0.501,0.598,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>COMENTANDO LOS DEPORTES
Además de acomodar en estos momentos a los
protagonistas del próximo bout por el título mundial
de los heavy-weight, es eentro de operaciones del ter
cer hombre de la división: Cassius Clay. 
Doug Jones que tendrá lugar el 13 de marzo en el
Madison Square Garden será transmitido por televi
sión en circuito cerrado. Chris Dundee prepara el Au
ditorium de Miami Beach y el de North Miami Beach
para que los fanáticos puedan disfrutar del mismo
al tiempo que se desarrolla en Nueva York. En una
conversación telefónica con una agencia cablegrafica
de la ciudad imperial Clay se refirió a la huelga
de periódicos que afecta a la gran metrópoli y dijo:
“Cuando llegue el viernes a Nueva York iré al mu
nicipio y pediré permiso para arreglar el problema,
Yo considero a la huelga una afrenta personal para
mi. Toda esa gente quiere leer acerca de mi y ver
mi fotografía. Tiene que haber miles de fotografías
mías para que las vean”.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1963-03-14/ed-1/?sp=33&q=cassius+clay+undefeated</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CASSIUS HUMAN AFTER ALL, NARROW DECISION PROVES
The black
Caddy pulled up to the entrance of the
Miami Beach Auditorium nearly two hours
before the closed-circuit telecast of the
Cassius Clay-Doug Jones fight In New York
was to begin. 
Cassius Clay bounces a left off the contorted
chin of Doug Jones in the 10th round of their
heavyweight fight last night in Madison
Square! Garden. It was this round which
Cassius Human After All,
Narrow Decision Proves
NEW YORK Mat 14
Clay balloon has been punc
tated. The self proclaimed
“greatest heavyweight” is hu
man after all.
There were no knockouts, no
knockdowns, no "total annlhi-
latlon,” and brash Cassius was
lucky to get a thin, lustily
booed decision in 10 rounds
over hard-working Doug Jones
of New York at Madison Square
Garden last night.
At times Clay looked like a
novice both at long range and
inside. His bombs didn’t explode
and he had to rally furiously
in the final two rounds to get
the unanimous verdict.
"Clay showed me that I’ll get
locked up for murder if we’re
ever matched," was the com
ment of Liston, who saw the
igored circuit telecast in Miami
beach.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn79000083/1963-03-23/ed-1/?sp=7&q=clay%2C+cassius+olympics&r=-0.138,0.178,0.563,0.359,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WANT CASSIUS TO FIGHT IN ITALY
Cassius Clay of Louisville was of
fered $80,000 Monday to come to
Rome and meet Italy’s all-con
quering Franco DePiccoli in a
I battle of Olympic champions.
“Let Clay come to Italy,” said
the 26-year-old DePiccoli. “Frank
ly, I don’t think he'll last three
rounds.”
The husky Italiain won the
Olympic heavyweight crown while
Clay took the light heavyweight
title in the 1960 games in Rome.
Since the Olympics Clay has
won all 8 of his pro fights and
is the No. 2 ranking heavyweight
contender. DePiccoli, a left-hand
er, is undefeated in 21 fights. He
is ranked 10th.
Rino Tommasi, the Italian’s
manager, said he made the offer
to Clay through Dewey Fragetta,
the internatinal boxing agent in
New York.
“I don’t consider Clay a top
fighter,” said DePiccoli. “I saw
him at the Olympics and I wasn’t
the least impressed. He may be a
better boxer than I am but I am
stronger.
“Of course I can make mis
takes. But I don’t think Signor
Clay is unbeatable.”
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025327/1963-03-29/ed-1/?sp=16&q=cassius+clay</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CASSIUS BROUGHT BACK BOXING TO LIFE
CLAY is a handsome youngster
who said he will ot be satisfied
until he becomes the -richest of
all heavyweight champions.
‘When the referee raised Cassius
Clay’s arm. in victory at the end
of his fight with Doug Jones, the
18,000 fans at Madison Square
Garden. demonstrated their dis
approval by bombarding the ring
with peanuts, programs, cups and
sssorted garbage.
The winning pitcher was E.
Hendricks. C. Asencio got the loss.
that’s all that counts.
Not surprisingly, Clay’s bitter
est critics were the same ones
who had been most lavish in their
praise for him. They felt that
Clay had conned them played
them for chumps.
In away, they are correct. But,
on the other hand, they got just
what they deserved. After all,
they were the ones who pro
claimed Cassius Clay as some kind
of a superman after he had
knocked out a few mediocre fight
ers. More reserved writers took
a “wait and see” attitude about
Clay.
What his enemies seem to over
look is the fact that boxing is a
business. Something that young
Cassius Clay keeps in mind at all
times.
Everyone is always eomplain
ing about the sad state of box
ing. The turnout even for cham
pionship bout is low. People
just seem to have lost interest
in boxing.
Cassius Clay, by himself, 're
vived‘that interest. People turned
out to see him fight. Everyone
wanted to get a look at the loud-
mouth. Most of them wanted to
see him get a beating. But Clay’
didn’t care about that. As long as
they showed up, he drew the
money.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1963-06-19/ed-1/?sp=34&q=cassius+marcellus+clay</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CLAY CALLS SHOT AGAIN IN BLOODY BOUT
Henry Cooper connects with a long right to the
jaw of Cassius Clay in one of many exchanges
during their heavyweight bout in London last
night. Cooper’s left eye already is bloody from
a cut opened in the third round. Although 
down in the fourth, Clay stopped the British heavyweight 
in the fifth to make another of his prophecies come true.
Cassius Marcellus Clay, the
punching prophet, beat Brit
ain’s Henry Cooper in the pre
dicted fifth round last night
and silenced a horrified crowd
in the fight that Liz Taylor
stopped.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87065526/1963-07-23/ed-1/?sp=4&q=knockout+cassius+clay</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PATTERSON FIGHT TAKES LITTLE LONGER THAN FIRST MATCH
LAS VEGAS. Nev. (UPI)—With
Floyd Patterson now demolished
as a challenger, heavyweight
champion Sonny Liston turned his
attention today to zipping the lip
of young Cassius Clay in a $7
million title fight at Philadel
phia’s Municipal Stadium, Sept.
30.
Big Sonny, whose ham-like fists
floored ex-champion Patterson
three times for a knockout at
2:10 of the first round Monday
night, will formally sign at Phila
delphia on Friday for his second
defense against cocky young Clay
of Kentucky, it was learned au
thoritatively today.
Thus will Liston make good on
a promise or was it a threat—
he made months ago when he
told Clay, “You’re next, loud,
mouth.”
Brash Cassius and glowering
Sonny will do their pen wielding
at Philadelphia at 2 p.m. EDT
Friday.
28th Straight Win
Sonny, who registered his 28th
straight victory and 23rd knock
out before a sellout 7,816 at the
Las Vegas Convention Center,
will receive 40 per cent of net
receipts from the Philadelphia,
fight. Clay has agreed to take
22* dcp cent
Patterson, who announced he'
will not retire despite two first j
round knockouts in his latest two
ring appearances, admitted he's
out of the title picture right now.
Surprisingly he added that he
gives Clay a chance to beat Son
ny in September because of
Clay’s youth, speed, weight
(about 210 pounds), and punch.
Bob Nilon, president of Inter
continental Promotions, Inc., ad
mitted today that Liston and Clay
already have come to terms and
that they will be in Philadelphia
Friday afternoon for a “news
conference.”
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1963-12-19/ed-1/?sp=71&q=cassius+clay+heavy+weight</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DRAFT PHYSICAL SET DEC 27 FOR CLAY
Cassius Clay, the heavy-
weight who throws poetry and
punches with almost equal
abandon, is scheduled to have
his draft physical December 27,
Selective Service headquarters
announced yesterday.
Cassius, who is scheduled to
fight Heavyweight Champion
Sonny Liston in February, was
ordered to appear at 39 White
hall street at 7 am. for the
physical.
If he passes the physical he
will have 10 days to decide
whether to go into the Army
so rtwo years or join a Nation
al Guard or Reserve unit.
    </text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1961-07-16/ed-1/seq-172/#date1=1756&index=1&rows=20&words=Cassius+Clay&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=CASSIUS+CLAY+&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>SPORTS ON TV 
  Home viewers will get a delayed
look (via tape) of the United States-
Russian track and field meet now
going on this week end in Moscow.
The TV report will be seen Saturday
(July 22) on ABC’s Wide World of
Sports series, 5 p.m., WMAL—7.
The program highlights an active
week of sport activities, among them
a night bailgame with the New York
Yankees (Tuesday, WTOP—9), the
Laconia, N. H., motorcycle races
(Thursday, WTOP—9) and a look
at ex-Olympic champ turned pro,
Cassius Clay (Saturday, WMAL—7).
ABC’s Wide World of Sports, in
cidentally, will follow the Moscow
meet with a report (July 29) of the
Japanese All-Star baseball game at
Nagoya, Japan.
And the first show in August on
this popular series will be from
Cheyenne, where cameras will record
the colorful action at the Frontier
Days rodeo.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1963-12-01/ed-1/seq-272/#date1=1756&index=6&rows=20&words=CASSIUS+CLAY&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=CASSIUS+CLAY+&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>THE JERRY LEWIS SHOW.
Comedy-variety. 2 Hours. Live entertain
ment with Jerry and special guest Cas
sius Clay.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84021918/1960-10-14/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&index=10&rows=20&words=Cassius+Clay&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=CASSIUS+CLAY+&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>Cassius Clay, Olympic heavy
weight champion, signed for his
first professional bout, a six
rounder against Tunney Hun
saker, Oct. 29 in Louisville, Ky.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84021918/1962-09-14/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&index=15&rows=20&words=Cassius+Clay&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=CASSIUS+CLAY+&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>MOOR E-CLAY BOUT AT COLISEUM
LOS ANGELES - Aging Archie
Moore and young Cassius Clay
will hold their Oct. 23 fight in
the Los Angeles Coliseum under
terms of an agreement approved
by the Coliseum Commission.
The pact, provides for a rental
of SIO,OOO for the first $200,000
and 7 1/2 per cent of receipts
over that.
The 12-round battle will mark
the second time the Stadium
has been used for boxing in its
30-year history.
A bout in 1960 drew 37,500
fans and a gate of $383,060.
The Moore-Clay fight is ex
pected to draw about 30,000.
Moore is guaranteed $75,000
or 35 per cent of the gate, which
ever is greater. Clay will get
$40,000 or 25 per cent.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020662/1963-07-24/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&index=18&rows=20&words=Cassius+Clay&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=CASSIUS+CLAY+&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>Cassius Clay Puts
In Unexpected Appearance
At Liston’s Victory Party
LAS VEGAS, Ncv. UFI — “This,”
—announced lippy Cassius Clay,
“was not a heavyweight champion
ship fight. It was just an elimina
tion to see who’s going to fight
me.”
Clay, the noisy, unbeaten con
tender from Louisville, made the
remark after putting in an un
expected appearance at Sonny
Liston’s victory party Monday
night, following the champion’s
one-round knockout of Floyd
Patterson.
Clay said he showed up at the
victory celebration “just to make
him (Liston) mad.”
He shouldered his way through
the crowd to where Liston was
sitting with some friends and told
the massive champion: “You’re
just a sucker. My brother could
nave beaten Floyd Patterson.”
Liston, in a rare burst of humor,
invited:
“Come over here and sit on my
knee and finish your oragne juice.”
Some further words were ex
changed and at one point Liston
rose to his feet and assumed a
mock fighting pose. Friends moved
between them.
Clay stole much of the thunder
from the fight even before it start
ed.
Clay stepped into the ring while
the announcer was introducing
famous boxers who were at ring
side. The fistic poet waved to
the crowd and shook hands with
Patterson.
Then he started for Liston with
his hand out — but suddenly re
treated in mock fear and bolted
from the ring.
</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-eiffel-tower</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025121/1889-04-02/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Eiffel+Tower+France+French+Paris+Worlds+Fair&st=text&r=0.14,0.022,0.423,0.404,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE EIFFEL TOWER
In view of the assurance of a
creditable representation of Hawaii
both in productions and person
agesat the Universal Exhibition of
this year in Paris a few facts rela
tive to the EiffeUower culled from
a late English paper may be of local
interest
The tower is named after its pro
jector Mr Eiffel now President of
the French Association of Engineers
He is famed in part -for the design
ing of a great bridge at Bordeaux
Although the Eiffel tower was orig
inally the conception mainly of an
ambition likened to that of Ameri
cans by the English paper referred
to for having the highest structure
in the world it was also early as
sumed that it would have uses in the
interest of science It is claimed
and anticipated that it will be very
raluable for observatory purposes
owing to the perfect clearness of the
air at its summit
The tower is to be one thousand
feet in height At the date of the
description here drawn upon it had
attained an altitude of 738 feet or
162 feet higher than any other build
ing on earth There were 180 men
employed then in its construction
100 preparing the lifts at the base
and 80 riveting the perfectly fitted
parts at top To avoid fatiguing the
workmen aloft in descending several
times a day for food a restaurant is
fitted up at a height of about 400
feet There are to bo four perman
ent restaurants for the refreshment
of visitors on the first stage of the
tower
A spiral stairway runs from the
ground to the summit of the tower
but it is believed that few if any in
experienced heads will be able to en
dure the strain of going round and
round or looking down from the
giddy heights Therefore there are
to be mechanical lifts to the top
four to the first stage two to the
second and thence one to the sum
mit the crown of observation The
final lift will have a capacity of 65
persons I1 ares will be 6 francs to
the first stage and 5 francs to the
top to be reduced on Sundays to 1
franc and 3 francs respectively No
visitors are allowed during construc
tion except on Sundays owing to
danger of accident from a hammer
or bolt falling from aloft Mr iffol
pays a weekly visit to thoworks The
workmeu have to endure severe cold
at the summit whore the thermome
ter sometimes registers several de
grees below zero
The panoramic view to be obtained
of the beautiful city of Paris and
environs froin the top of the Eiffel
tower must be loft to the readers
imagination until assisted by ac
counts from the Hawaiian Commis
sioners Col Spalding and Hon J
A Cummins or unofficial visitors
from these isies or descriptive writ
ers in the foreign press after ex
periencing the sensations of the
sublime ascension and prospect
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91068084/1889-04-26/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+Exhibition+1000+Feet+High+France+French+Worlds+Fair&st=text&r=-0.062,0.547,0.643,0.615,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NEARLY 1000 FEET HIGH THE GREAT EIFFEL TOWER AT THE PARIS EXPOSITION
How the Colossal Structure, Just
Completed, was Erected.
The great Eiffel tower at the Paris Exhi
bition has just been completed, and a de
scription of the colossal structure, with an
account of the way it was built, and a sketch
of its constructor, will bo appropriate at this
time. It is scarcely necessary to say that the
Eiffel tower is by far the highest structure in
the world. It presents a decidedly unique ap
pearance, too in general outline not unlike a
stack of four gigantic muskets with their
butts well and solidly spread and their bay
onets joining at their tips.
The Eiffel tower stands in the Champ de
Mars, almost on the left bank of the river
Seine, just in the rear of the Quai d'Orsay,
and in fact a part of its foundation is sunk
through an old arm of the river, which lias
been filled in these many years. Its base
covers a plot of ground 328 feet square, or
nearly two and a half acres in extent.
It Ls really at the base a group of four tow
ers, each nearly fifty feet square, placed at
the corners of the plot of ground, and in
clining toward each other as they rise at an
angle of fifty-four degrees. Each tower con
sists of four columns, bound together by
trusswork, and each column rests on a
masonry pier which is so built that the weight
of the column rests upon it squarely and not
at an ancle.
As the tower is 0S4 feet high. it will be
seen that the matter of providing a solid
foundation was one of great importance.
There was a lot of boring and digging befon
the spot upon which the tower stands was
finally selected.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060190/1889-05-07/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Expo+Exhibition+Worlds+Fair&st=text&r=-0.306,-0.081,1.611,1.611,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1900-05-20/ed-1/?sp=43&q=Feet+Tower+Eiffel+Paris+France+French+Worlds+Fair+Exhibition&st=text&r=0.604,-0.016,0.384,0.459,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>AT THE FEET OF THE TOWER
  Round about the huge feet of the Eiffel Tower
will be found the pavilions of those countries
which did not find a place in the Rue des Na
tions—the Swiss chalet, built completely of wood,
surrounded with balconies and terraces, like the
great Alpine chalets. It is not an official pa
vilion for receptions, but a meeting place for
the Swiss visiting Paris; the pavilion of San
Marino, the little republic dovetailed into the
kingdom of Italy, containing cereals, wine, oil,
honey, lace, embroidery, pictures, furniture, uni
forms and various works of art highly creditable
to a country of only five thousand inhabitants;
the pavilion of Siam adds its Oriental stamp to
the peculiar architectural macedoine; Morocco
is divided into two distinct arts the Imperial
Pavilion and the annexes, containing restau
rant, cafes and shops.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85032018/1894-01-31/ed-1/?sp=15&q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Worlds+Fair+1900+Exhibition&st=text&r=-0.304,-0.08,1.608,1.608,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE WORLD'S FAIR IN 1900
  Already the air is' filled with rumors
respecting the exposition of 1900, says
a Paris letter in the Philadelphia Tel
graph. Already are the moans of the
Parisians rending the air beforehand,
for it is a Parisian peculiarity to detest
world's fairs in general, and those held
in their own city in particular. Quoth
a miserable native in heartrending ac
cents: "Whenever there is a great ex
hibition all our taxes go up-rtempo-rarily
we are told, but never by an ac
cident do they go down. I paid three
hundred and eighty francs in '77,
and for the same premises my taxes
are now three thousand and odd. We
are overrun by tourists; we are crowd
ed out of all the theaters; the cabmen
all go on strike; the cafes all put up
their prices.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040198/1899-02-03/ed-1/?sp=7&q=Eiffel+Tower+France+French+Paris+Exhibition+Worlds+Fair+Ladder+Clouds&st=text&r=-0.11,-0.072,1.242,1.483,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A LADDER FROM THE CLOUDS
Bach Will Be the Appearance of the
Eiffel Tower of Parts When
Painted.
The Eiffel tower, say the gentlemen
of esthetic temperament, must go.
The Eiffel tower, say the gentlemen
who know the law, must stay for some
years yet. The Eiffel tower, say the
esthetes. Is ugly, discouraging to the
eye and an all-round nightmare. "Scaf
fold I cries the carper. "Down with it
It has no place in esthetic Paris,"
"Impossible! objects the law. "When
the company took a lease of it they
got it for a term of 20 years.. You
can't break the lease, and the time is
nowhere up.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1903-10-25/ed-1/?sp=24&q=Eiffel+Tower+Doomed+Rocks+Wind+Paris+France+French+Gustav</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>EIFFEL TOWER DOOMED. IT ROCKS IN THE WIND
THE Eiffel Tower must come down.
The authorities of Paris have so decreed.
This iron spire, the tallest structure in the
world, and the engineering feat of the last cen
tury, .i regarded as a dangerous plaything.
When a high wind blows from the south the great
ribbed structure trembles like a frightened horse.
But let a stiff breeze come bowling down from the
north and the tower vibrates until the china rattles in
the cafes, and to those in the observatory at the apex the
sensation is that of a ship fossed by heavy seas.
The fact that the tower is more'sensitive to a wind
from the north than from the south is regarded as proof
of the structural weakness, and from this springs the
theory of danger of collapse.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1907-05-18/ed-1/?sp=26&q=Dangerous+Painting+World+Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Republic+Gustav&st=text&r=-0.096,-0.045,1.192,1.424,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MOST DANGEROUS PAINTING JOB IN THE WORLD
A painter has Just fallen from the Eiffel
Tower. Four more men must fall to make
the awful average of the most dangerous
painting Job in the world?repeated every
six years only.
They are repainting the Eiffel Tower,
and all Paris is concerned about the color,
on which depends whether the gigantic
mass of iron shall be the eyesore or the
glory of the capital.
Its first shade was "dead leaf," In 1889.
When the sun lit it up to hazy golden with
an unreal effect of Jeweler's fragility, even
the artists who now corse it admitted that
the Eiffel Tower had its nobility.
In 1896, after immense discussion, they
repainted It orange, magnetic currents
even more than light and weather having
turned it to a dingy chocolate, heavy and
obtrusive. In strong sun the orange
showed gleaming copper or red gold. Oscar
Wilde declared It magnificent. Puvis de
Chavannes threatened to blow It up with
dynamite. From this period dated the bad
name the tower acquired as a colossal
piece of engineering vulgarity, usurping
the artistic note of Paris.
Then, for the exposition, they painted it
"sun color." In bright lights the tower
became a thing of glory once again.
"All Depends Upon the Faint."
"All depends upon the paint!" declares
the city's architect, Bouyard, "a fact
which shows the utter inartistic character
of the Titanic intruder.
The Library of Congress
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016810/1911-03-11/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Tower+Saved+Eiffel+Structure+Paris+France+French+Wireless&st=text&r=-0.061,0,1.123,1.341,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DEFIES ITS GLOOMY PROPHET
Huge Eiffel Structure Converted
into Wireless Station.
From its Top Messages Are Sent
5,000 MilesSoon to Be in
Touch With the United
States.
Paris.From the summit of the Eif
fel tower, 984 feet in the air, scien
tists communicate with ships nearly
5,000 miles out at sea. It is radio-tel
egraphy which makes it possible to
transmit to all vessels within that dis
tance a given time, say the hour of
noon, mathematically exact within the
tenth of a second, the speed of the
Hertzian waves being almost equal to
that of light.
The method now used at the Eiffel
tower was first experimented with last
June. An increase in the power of
electric batteries and improvements
in other instruments enabled radio
telegraphic signals to be sent and re
ceived.
These
two clocks twice every dayat 11
The Eiffel Tower.
o'clock in the morning and at midnight
will signal the time to the four
points of the compass by means of an
electrical apparatus on the summit of
the Eiffel tower.
The Library of Congress
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016810/1911-03-11/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Tower+Saved+Eiffel+Structure+Paris+France+French+Wireless&st=text&r=-0.061,0,1.123,1.341,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TOWER TO BE SAVED
  Huge Eiffel Structure Converted
into Wireless Station.
From its Top Messages Are Sent
5,000 MilesSoon to Be in
Touch With the United
States.
Paris.From the summit of the Eif
fel tower, 984 feet in the air, scien
tists communicate with ships nearly
5,000 miles out at sea. It is radio-tel
egraphy which makes it possible to
transmit to all vessels within that dis
tance a given time, say the hour of
noon, mathematically exact within the
tenth of a second, the speed of the
Hertzian waves being almost equal to
that of light.
The method now used at the Eiffel
tower was first experimented with last
June. An increase in the power of
electric batteries and improvements
in other instruments enabled radio
telegraphic signals to be sent and re
ceived.
These
two clocks twice every dayat 11
The Eiffel Tower.
o'clock in the morning and at midnight
will signal the time to the four
points of the compass by means of an
electrical apparatus on the summit of
the Eiffel tower.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1915-03-18/ed-1/seq-45/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=Eiffel+Tower&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=EIFFEL+TOWER&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
    <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1917-04-23/ed-2/seq-9/#date1=1756&index=5&rows=20&words=Eiffel+tower&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=EIFFEL+TOWER&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>OUTBURSTS OF EVERETT TRUE 
    Stars and stripes hung be
side tri-color on Eiffel tower Sunday
afternoon, while formal salute of 21
guns was fired in its. honor. It was
United States day in Paris and Amer
ican flags were everywhere.
New York. Local newspapers
adopt resolution criticizing press
censorship provision of espionage
bill "assault upon very foundation of
our free institutions, freedom of
thought and freedom of speech
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1948-02-29/ed-1/seq-111/#date1=1756&index=7&rows=20&words=Eiffel+Tower&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=EIFFEL+TOWER&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
    <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1940-06-14/ed-1/seq-9/#date1=1756&index=8&rows=20&words=Eiffel+Tower&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=EIFFEL+TOWER&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>To Americans, Paris, which fell
to the Germans today is the
Louvre (a' magnificent art mu
seum), the Tuileries, the Hotel
des Invalides, the opera, the
Eiffel Tower, the University of
Paris, the Cathedral of Notre
Dame, the Place de la Concorde
(where Louis XVI and Marie
Antoinette were beheaded); it
means gay Montmartre, broad
boulevards and the cool of the
Bois de Boulogne.
To 3,000,000 Frenchmen and
women Paris is home; to 42.000,
000 it is the Theater Francais,
the Pantheon (temple of honor
to the great men of France), the
capital; the center of banking,
commerce, industry.
Caesar in his chronicles tells
how Paris then named Lutetiai
was burned in the Gaelic war of
independence in 52 B. C. Bar
barian invasions destroyed Paris
in the 3d century. The Franks
took Paris in the 5th century, the
Normans in the 9th. The Black
Death and the Hundred Years
War, in the 13th and 14t,h cen
turies, both ravaged Paris. In
1422 England took Paris, held it
against Joan of Arc. In the 16th
century came the wars of re
ligion. Louis XIV and Napoleon
| made Paris the hub of a Euro
pean empire.
From 1871 to 1873 the victorious
Germans occupied Paris, collect
ed $1,000,000,000 in reparations.
In 1914-1918 the Germans bomb
ed and shelled but never cap
tured the city. In addition there
have been revolutions in Paris
and generals have marched out
to battle over much of the world.
Since Napoleonic times, Paris
has increased sixfold in popula
tion. Its 3.000,000 people give it
the greatest population density
of any major city.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-06-29/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&index=3&rows=20&words=Eiffel+tower&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=EIFFEL+TOWER&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>French are reported to have sta
tioned parrots on the Eiffel tower to
give warning against the approach of
aeroplanes. The birds bristle and
screech when the machines approach
long before they are detected by hu
man lookouts. 
</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
